Charles B. Davenport Papers ca.1903-1940 Mss.B.D27
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Charles B. Davenport Papers, 1878-1944; 43 linear feet (Box 1-97)
  - Gini, Corrado, 1923-1933; 111 items (Box 41)
    Conferences and symposia; Eugenics; Human genetics; International Congress of Eugenics -- Third Congress; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs -- International Federation of Eugenics Organizations; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; World War I -- Impact on science
  - Giuffrida-Ruggeri, V. (Box 41)
  - Glaser, Otto, 1916-1920; 45 items (Box 41)
    Eugenics; International Congress of Eugenics -- Second Congress; Race Betterment Foundation; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
  - Glasgow, J. Wesley (Box 41)
  - Glen Cove, N.Y., Non-Partisan Taxpayers Association (Box 41)
  - Glover, L. F. (Box 41)
  - Glover, Nelle (Box 41)
  - Godard, George S. (Box 41)
  - Goddard, Henry H., 1909-1921; 148 items (Box 41)
    Behavioral genetics, IQ; Committee activities; Eugenics; Human genetics; Research support; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Goddard, James B. (Box 41)
  - Goddard, Mary A. (Box 41)
  - Goddard, P. E. (Box 41)
  - Godlewski, E., Jr. (Box 41)
  - Goeckerman, W. H. (Box 41)
  - Goethe, C. M., 1924-1930; 50 items (Box 41)
    Eugenics; Political issues; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Goetsch, Emil (Box 41)
  - Goldfarb, Abraham J. (Box 41)
  - Goldschmidt, R. (Richard Benedict), 1914-1933; 22 items (Box 41)
    Biographical and personal data; Genetics -- Lymantria; Human genetics; World War I -- Impact on science
  - Goldsmith, William M. (Box 41)
  - Good, Albert H. (Box 41)
  - Goodale, H. D. (Hubert Dana), 1911-1933; 86 items (Box 41)
    Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Conferences and symposia; Mount Hope Farm; Physiology; Poultry genetics
  - Goodall, George L. (Box 41)
  - Goodyear, Mrs. Nelson (Box 41)
  - Gorgas, William C. (Box 42)
  - Gortner, Ross A. (Ross Aiken), 1909-1941; 96 items (Box 42)
    Biochemistry and organic chemistry; Biographical and personal data; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Harris, J. A.; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Poultry genetics; Publication; Teaching -- University of Minnesota; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Gosney, E. S. (Box 42)
  - Goto, R. (Box 42)
  - Gotto, Mrs. S. (Sybil), 1910-1923; 103 items (Box 42)
    Biographical and personal data; Committee activities; Eugenics; Human genetics; International Congress of Eugenics -- First Congress; International Congress of Eugenics -- Second Congress; Publication; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
  - Gould, Charles W., 1921-1931; 47 items (Box 42)
    Bibliographical matters; Eugenics; Genetics; Human genetics; Political issues; Poultry genetics; Recommendations
  - Gould, Joseph F., 1913-1916; 48 items (Box 42)
    Anthropology; Human evolution, physical anthropology; Human genetics; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Govaerts, A. P. (Albert P.), 1921-1931; 83 items (Box 42)
    Behavioral genetics, IQ; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Embryology, developmental genetics; Eugenics; International Congress of Eugenics -- Third Congress; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Gowen, John W. (Box 42)
  - Gozenbach, W. von (Box 42)
  - Graf, Ludwig von (Box 42)
  - Graham, J. C. (Box 42)
  - Grant, Madison, 1904-1933; 247 items (Box 42)
    Anthropology; Eugenics; Human evolution, physical anthropology; Human genetics; International Congress of Eugenics -- Second Congress; National Research Council; Political issues; Publication; Reviews; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
  - Graves, Frank P. (Box 42)
  - Graves, William W. (Box 42)
  - Gravier, Charles (Box 42)
  - Gray, Albert (Box 42)
  - Gray, Horace (Box 42)
  - Green, Bernard R. (Box 43)
  - Green, C. V. (Box 43)
  - Greene, Jerome D. (Box 43)
  - Greenman, Milton J., 1906-1932; 71 items (Box 43)
    Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Committee activities; Editorial matters; International Congress of Eugenics -- Third Congress; Publication
  - Gregory, Herbert E. (Box 43)
  - Gregory, William K., 1912-1933; 560 items (Box 43)
    Anthropology; Human evolution, physical anthropology; International Congress of Eugenics -- Third Congress; Publication; Recommendations -- Harris, Reginald; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Solicitations for support or contribution; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; Zoology -- Gorillas
  - Grier, Norman MacDowell, 1914-1934; 65 items (Box 43)
    Academic freedom; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Educational matters -- Dartmouth College; Publication; Recommendations; Requests for aid in finding positions; Teaching; Zoology
  - Griffin, Laurence E. (Box 43)
  - Grossman, William (Box 43)
  - Grosvenor, Gilbert H. (Box 43)
  - Groszmann, Maximilian P. E. (Box 43)
  - Grout, Charles S. (Box 44)
  - Grover, Frederick O. (Box 44)
  - Gudernatsch, J. F. (Box 44)
  - Gudger, E. W. (Box 44)
  - Guggenheim Memorial Foundation (Box 44)
  - Gulick, John T. (Box 44)
  - Gulick, Luther H. (Box 44)
  - Gulick, Sydney S. (Box 44)
  - Gun, W. T. J. (Box 44)
  - Günther, Hans F. K. (Box 44)
  - Gurgel do Amaral, S. (Box 44)
  - Guthrie, C. C. (Box 44)
  - Guyer, M. F. (Box 44)
  - Hadden, C., Jr. (Box 44)
  - Haddon, A. C. (Box 44)
  - Hadley, Arthur T. (Box 44)
  - Hadley, Philip B. (Box 44)
  - Haeckel, Ernst (Box 44)
  - Haecker, V. (Box 44)
  - Hague, Arnold (Box 44)
  - Hahn, Rosina (Box 44)
  - Haight, C. W. (Box 44)
  - Hale, Edwin H. (Box 44)
  - Hale, Fred (Box 44)
  - Hale, George E. (Box 44)
  - Hale, William H. (Box 44)
  - Hall, C. W. (Box 44)
  - Hall, Daniel (Box 44)
  - Hall, E. H. (Box 44)
  - Hall, G. Stanley (Box 44)
  - Hall, Gertrude E. (Box 44)
  - Hall, Harvey Monroe (Box 44)
  - Hall, James (Box 44)
  - Hall, Prescott Farnsworth (Box 44)
  - Hall, Robert W. (Box 44)
  - Halle, Louis J. (Box 44)
  - Hallowell, A. Irving (Box 44)
  - Hamaker, J. I. (Box 44)
  - Hammett, Frederick S. (Box 45)
  - Hammond, Mrs. John Hays (Box 45)
  - Hansen, Sören (Box 45)
  - Hanson, Frank Blair (Box 45)
  - Hapgood, Norman (Box 45)
  - Hargitt, Charles W. (Box 45)
  - Hargitt, George T. (Box 45)
  - Harmer, Sidney F. (Box 45)
  - Harper, E. H. (Box 45)
  - Harper, R. A. (Box 45)
  - Harper, Roland M. (Box 45)
  - Harper, William R. (Box 45)
  - Harriman, Carol Averill (Box 45)
  - Harriman, E. H. (Edward Henry) (Box 45)
  - Harriman, E. Rowland (Box 45)
  - Harriman, Mary Williamson [Mrs. E. H.], 1910-1932; 7 folders (Box 45)
    Business; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Eugenics; Eugenics Record Office; Research support
    - Folder 1, 1910 (Box 45)
      - Letter to Mrs. Harriman from Cold Spring Harbor, 1910 Aug. 21 (Box 45)
    - Folder 2, 1911 (Box 45)
    - Folder 3, 1911 (Box 45)
    - Folder 4, 1912 (Box 45)
    - Folder 5, 1914-1915 (Box 45)
    - Folder 6, 1916-1924 (Box 45)
    - Folder 7, 1924 (Box 45)
  - Harriman, Mrs. W. Averill (Box 45)
  - Harriman, William Averill (Box 45)
  - Harrington, C. L., 1906-1909; 2 folders (72 items) (Box 45)
    Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences; Brooklyn Polytechnic Institute; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Publication
  - Harris, B. Malcolm (Box 45)
  - Harris, Benjamin R. (Box 45)
  - Harris, Reginald G., 1919-1923; 60 items (Box 45)
    Biographical and personal data; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Graduate study; Recommendations; Research support; Teaching; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Harris, Seale (Box 45)
  - Harris, Thomas J. (Box 45)
  - Harris, Thomas P. (Box 45)
  - Harris, William (Box 46)
  - Harrison, Charles C. (Box 46)
  - Harrison, Effie (Box 46)
  - Harrison, J. W. H. (Box 46)
  - Harrison, Ross G., 1903-1933; 247 items (Box 46)
    Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Editorial matters; Graduate study; Long Island Biological Association; Marine Biological Laboratory, Woods Hole; National Academy of Sciences; National Research Council; Recommendations -- Bernstein, Felix; Recommendations -- Blakeslee, Albert Francis; Referee's report; World War I -- Impact on science
  - Harrison, W. G. (Box 46)
  - Harrison and Sons (Box 46)
  - Harshberger, John W. (Box 46)
  - Hart, C. A. (Box 46)
  - Hart, William H. H. (Box 46)
  - Harting, J. E. (Box 46)
  - Hartline, D. S. (Box 46)
  - Hartman, Carl (Box 46)
  - Harvard Days, 1887-1939; 33 items (Box 46)
    Biographical and personal data; Graduate study -- Harvard University; Harvard University; Research support; Teaching -- Harvard University
  - Harvard University (Box 46)
    - Bigelow, M. A. On the effect of light upon the growth of animals (Box 46)
    - Brewster. Notes on some tooth variations in certain of the Suidae (Box 46)
    - Cannon, W. B. Some experiments in photoxis (Box 46)
    - Earle, Mabel L (Box 46)
    - Jennings, H. S. Experimental morphology (Box 46)
    - Sargent, P. E. Control of the rate of regeneration in oligochaetes. (Box 46)
    - Waite, F. C. On the acclimization of organisms to dense solutions (Box 46)
  - Harvard University Lecture Notes, Includes seven (7) notebooks. (Box 47-49)
    - Cell Division by Density, (?), Electricity, Heat, Pressure & Molar Agents; Movements of Amoebae (Box 47)
    - Corr. variation, Diff. Gravity, Color, Xeny, Isolation, Spec. Problems with Standard Deviation (Box 47)
    - Differentiation (Box 47)
    - Experiments with eggs and fertilization (Box 47)
    - Hybrids & Laws of Heredity, 2 folders (Box 47)
    - Linnaean Classification System (Box 47)
    - Misc. on Species, Mutation & Evolution (Box 47)
    - Morphogenesis (Box 47)
    - Preparation Lists (Box 48)
    - Sports (Box 48)
    - Statistical Methods; Skew curves; Mosquitoes; class experiments (Box 48)
    - Variation (Box 48)
    - Vertebrate Anatomy (Box 48)
    - Zoology marks from multiple years and classes (Box 48)
    - Zoology I lectures, 3 folders (Box 48)
    - Zoology II (Box 49)
    - Zoology III: History of Comparative Anatomy (Box 49)
    - Zoology IV: Introduction to Methods (Box 49)
    - Zoology 11, Lecture 34: Anatomy, behavior of Animals (Box 49)
    - Notebooks, 7 volumes (Box 49)
  - Harvard University Research, 1891-1892; 7 folders (Box 50)
    Graduate study -- Harvard University; Harvard University; Regeneration; Zoology
    - Bryozoa drawings (Box 50)
    - Drawings, misc. (Box 50)
    - Miscellany (Box 50)
    - Obelia experiment (Box 50)
    - Regeneration (Box 50)
    - Regeneration - Newport (Box 50)
    - Worms (Box 50)
  - Harvey, E. Newton (Box 50)
  - Harvey, Ethel Brown (Box 50)
  - Haskell, William N. (Box 50)
  - Haskin, Frederic J. (Box 50)
  - Hassam, Frederick F. (Box 50)
  - Hastings, William W. (Box 50)
  - Hatai, S. (Box 50)
  - Haustein, Hans (Box 50)
  - Hawkes, A. Merritt (Box 50)
  - Hawkes, Ernest W. (Box 50)
  - Hayes, Samuel P. (Box 50)
  - Hayes, Seth (Box 50)
  - Haynes, John Randolph (Box 50)
  - Hays, Will H. (Box 50)
  - Hays, Willet Martin, 1902-1924; 13 folders (494 items) (Box 50)
    Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Eugenics; Genetics; Political issues; Requests for aid in finding positions; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs -- American Breeders' Association; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
    - Folder 1, 1902-1906 (Box 50)
    - Folder 2, 1907 (Box 50)
    - Folder 3, 1908 (Box 50)
    - Folder 4, 1908-1909 (Box 50)
    - Folder 5, 1909-1910 (Box 50)
    - Folder 6, 1910 (Box 50)
    - Folder 7, 1910 (Box 50)
    - Folder 8, 1910-1911 (Box 50)
    - Folder 9, 1911 (Box 50)
    - Folder 10, 1911 (Box 50)
    - Folder 11, 1912 (Box 50)
    - Folder 12, 1912-1913 (Box 50)
    - Folder 13, 1913-1924 (Box 50)
  - Haywood, Harry (Box 51)
  - Heck, Chester R. (Box 51)
  - Heckscher, Aug. (Box 51)
  - Hedrick, U. P. (Box 51)
  - Hefferan, Mary (Box 51)
  - Hefner, R. A. (Box 51)
  - Hegner, Robert W. (Box 51)
  - Heidenheim, I. (Box 51)
  - Hektoen, Ludwig, 1924-1932; 6 folders (158 items) (Box 51)
    Committee activities; Human genetics; Physiology; Publication; Rat genetics; Solicitations for support or contribution
    - Folder 1, 1924 (Box 51)
    - Folder 2, 1925, January - February (Box 51)
    - Folder 3, 1925, March - April (Box 51)
    - Folder 4, 1925, May - 1926 (Box 51)
    - Folder 5, 1927 (Box 51)
    - Folder 6, 1928-1932 (Box 51)
  - Helff, O. M. (Box 51)
  - Henchman, Annie P. (Box 51)
  - Henderson, Charles (Box 51)
  - Henderson, George D. (Box 51)
  - Henderson, Ruth E. (Box 51)
  - Henderson, Yandell (Box 51)
  - Henn, Arthur W. (Box 51)
  - Henser, Frederick W. J. (Box 51)
  - Henshaw, Samuel, 1896-1922; 63 items (Box 51)
    Biographical and personal data; Committee activities; Poultry genetics; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
  - Herdman, W. A. (Box 51)
  - Hermann, P. (Box 51)
  - Hernandez, Pierre (Box 51)
  - Heron, David (Box 51)
  - Heron, W. T. (Box 51)
  - Herrick, C. Judson (Box 51)
  - Herrick, Francis H. (Box 51)
  - Herrman, Charles (Box 51)
  - Herskovits, Melville J. (Box 51)
  - Hertwig, Richard (Box 51)
  - Herwerden, M. A. van (Marianne A. van), 1920-1934; 3 folders (86 items) (Box 52)
    Biographical and personal data; Committee activities; Genetics; Human genetics; International Congress of Eugenics -- Second Congress; International Congress of Eugenics -- Third Congress; Publication; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Hess, Alfred F. (Box 52)
  - Heuyer, Georges (Box 52)
  - Hevesh, Jack (Box 52)
  - Hewlett, Louis (Box 52)
  - Hicks, Frederick E. (Box 52)
  - Hicks, Henry (Box 52)
  - Hicks, Isaac, and Son (Box 52)
  - Hickson, William J. (Box 52)
  - Higley, Mrs. Elmer E. (Box 52)
  - Hill, Joseph A. (Box 52)
  - Hill, Paul A. (Box 52)
  - Himes, Norman E. (Box 52)
  - Hitchcock, F. C. (Box 52)
  - Hodge, F. W. (Box 52)
  - Hoeber, Paul B., Inc. (Box 52)
  - Hoffman, Frederick L., 1917-1933; 3 folders (104 items) (Box 52)
    Anthropology; Committee activities; Human genetics; International Congress of Eugenics -- Second Congress; National Research Council; Statistics, biostatistics, biometrics; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; World War I -- Impact on science
  - Hoffman, G. von (Box 52)
  - Hollick, Arthur (Box 52)
  - Hollingworth, Leta S. (Box 52)
  - Holmes, Samuel J., 1909-1936; 2 folders (Box 52)
  - Holmes, W. H. (Box 52)
  - Henry Holt and Co., 1909-1938; 6 folders (Box 52)
    Embryology, developmental genetics; Eugenics; Evolution; Human genetics; Publication
    - Folder 1, 1909-1911 (Box 52)
    - Folder 2, 1911-1912 (Box 52)
    - Folder 3, 1912-1922 (Box 52)
    - Folder 4, 1923-1935 (Box 52)
    - Folder 5, 1936 (Box 52)
    - Folder 6, 1936-1938 (Box 52)
  - Hooker, Davenport (Box 52)
  - Hooker, Louis L. (Box 52)
  - Hooper, Franklin W., 1899-1914; 5 folders (113 items) (Box 52)
    Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Teaching
  - Hooton, E. A. (Earnest Albert), 1918-1935; 2 folders (59 items) (Box 52)
    Anthropology; Committee activities; Embryology, developmental genetics; International Congress of Eugenics -- Second Congress; International Congress of Genetics -- Fifth Congress; Reviews; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
  - Hornaday, William T., 1897-1926; 2 folders (Box 52)
  - Houssay, Bernardo A. (Bernardo Alberto) (Box 53)
  - Hovey, E. O. (Box 53)
  - Howard, L. O. (Leland Ossian), 1899-1923; 3 folders (124 items) (Box 53)
    American Association for the Advancement of Science; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
  - Howe, Freeland, Jr. (Box 53)
  - Howe, James Louis (Box 53)
  - Howe, Lucien (Box 53)
  - Howe, Reginald Heber, Jr. (Box 53)
  - Howell, Arthur H (Box 53)
  - Howells, William White (Box 53)
  - Hrdlička, Aleš, 1906-1936; 6 folders (277 items) (Box 53)
    Anthropology; Committee activities; Conferences and symposia; Editorial matters; Eugenics; Human evolution, physical anthropology; Human genetics; Laboratory techniques, equipment; National Academy of Sciences; National Research Council; Publication; Recommendations; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; World War I -- Impact on science
    - Folder 1, 1909-1916 (Box 53)
    - Folder 2, 1917-1923 (Box 53)
    - Folder 3, 1924-1925 (Box 53)
    - Folder 4, 1926-1929 (Box 53)
    - Folder 5, 1930-1934 (Box 53)
    - Folder 6, 1935-1936 (Box 53)
  - Hubbard, Marian E. (Box 53)
  - Huber, G. Carl (Box 53)
  - Hughes, Charles E. (Box 53)
  - Humphrey, J. E. (Box 53)
  - Humphreys, E. D. (Box 53)
  - Hunt, Ethyl I. (Box 53)
  - Hunt, Harrison R., 1915-1940; 3 folders (125 items) (Box 53)
    Academic freedom; Bibliographical matters; Biographical and personal data; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Committee activities; Eugenics; Human genetics; Rat genetics; Requests for aid in finding positions; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Teaching; University of Michigan
  - Hunt, J. Ramsay (Box 53)
  - Hunt, Reid (Box 53)
  - Huntington, Ellsworth (Box 53)
  - Huntington, Henry S. (Box 53)
  - Hurst, Charles C. (Box 53)
  - Hus, Henri (Box 53)
  - Hutchinson, Susan A., 1903-1924; 6 folders (Box 53-54)
    - Folder 1, 1903-1907 (Box 53)
    - Folder 2, 1907-1908 (Box 53)
    - Folder 3, 1909-1911 (Box 53)
    - Folder 4, 1911-1914 (Box 54)
    - Folder 5, 1914-1920 (Box 54)
    - Folder 6, 1920-1924 (Box 54)
  - Hutt, F. B. (Box 54)
  - Hyatt, Alpheus (Box 54)
  - Hyde, Ida H. (Box 54)
  - Ickes, Harold L. (Box 54)
  - Iljin, N. A. (Box 54)
  - Iltis, Hugo (Box 54)
  - Immigration Restriction League (Boston, Mass.) (Box 54)
  - Ingalls, Albert G (Box 54)
  - Insects (Drawings) (Box 54)
  - Institute of American Genealogy (Box 54)
  - International Association of Instructions and Investigators in Poultry Husbandry (Box 54)
  - International Auxiliary Language Association (Box 54)
  - International Boundary Commission (Box 54)
  - International Congress of Americanists (Box 54)
  - International Congress of Biology (Box 54)
  - International Congress of Entyomology, 4th (Box 54)
  - International Congress of Eugenics, 3rd: 1932: New York, 1930-1933; 12 folders (Box 54)
    Business; Committee activities; Conferences and symposia; Eugenics; International Congress of Eugenics -- Exhibits; International Congress of Eugenics -- Third Congress
    - International Congress of Eugenics, 3rd: 1932: New York, 3 folders (Box 54)
    - Committee on Reception & Entertainment, 4 folders (Box 54)
    - Exhibits (Box 54)
    - Finance Committee, 2 folders (Box 54)
    - Foreign Representatives (Box 54)
    - Publicity (Box 54)
  - International Congress of Genetics, 5th: 1927: Berlin (Box 54)
    International Congress of Genetics -- Fifth Congress
  - International Congress of Genetics, 6th: 1932: Ithaca, 1928-1932; 10 folders (Box 55)
    Committee activities; Conferences and symposia; International Congress of Eugenics -- Exhibits; International Congress of Genetics -- Sixth Congress; Publication; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
    - Committee of 100 (Box 55)
    - Exhibits Committee (Box 55)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 55)
    - Program Committee (Box 55)
    - Publication Committee (Box 55)
    - Publicity Committee (Box 55)
    - Transportation Committee (Box 55)
    - Votes, 3 folders (Box 55)
  - International Congress of Psychology, 9th, 10th (Box 55)
  - International Congress of Zoology, 7th, 2 folders (Box 55)
  - International Congress on Mental Hygiene, 1st (Box 55)
  - International Education Board (Box 55)
  - International Federation of Eugenic Organizations, 1924-1936; 33 folders (Box 55-57)
    Business; Committee activities; Eugenics; Human genetics; Political issues; Race crossing; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
    - Administrative secretary's report (Box 55)
    - Finances (Box 55)
    - Hodson, C. B. S., 1924-1927 (Box 55)
    - Hodson, C. B. S., 1928; 2 folders (Box 55)
    - Hodson, C. B. S., 1929; 2 folders (Box 55)
    - Hodson, C. B. S., 1930; 4 folders (Box 56)
    - Hodson, C. B. S., 1931; 2 folders (Box 56)
    - Hodson, C. B. S., 1932; 2 folders (Box 56)
    - Hodson, C. B. S., 1933 (Box 56)
    - Hodson, C. B. S., 1934 (Box 56)
    - Hodson, C. B. S., 1935 (Box 56)
    - Hodson, C. B. S., 1936 (Box 56)
    - Committee on Race Crossing, 6 folders (Box 56-57)
    - Meetings: 1928, Munich (Box 57)
    - Meetings: 1929, Rome (Box 57)
    - Meetings: 1930, Larmertree, Farnham, England (Box 57)
    - Meetings: 1932, New York (Box 57)
    - Meetings: 1934, Zurich (Box 57)
    - Meetings: 1936, Scheweningen, The Hague, Holland (Box 57)
    - Membership (Box 57)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 57)
    - Votes (Box 57)
  - International Geographical and Ethnological Congress (Box 57)
  - International Union for the Scientific Investigation of Population Problems (Box 57)
  - International Y.M.C.A. College (Box 57)
  - International Zoological Congress, 7th (Box 57)
  - Iowa Statistical Service (Box 57)
  - Ireland, Alleyne (Box 57)
  - Irvin and Mount (Box 57)
  - Isca, Arthur W. (Box 57)
  - Ishii, O. (Box 57)
  - Ishikawa, Chiyomatsu (Box 57)
  - Issel, Rafaela (Box 57)
  - Italia America Shipping Corp. (Box 57)
  - Ives, C. P., 2nd (Box 57)
  - Iwanow, E. (Box 57)
  - Jackman, Wilbur S. (Box 57)
  - Jackson, A. V. W. (Box 57)
  - Jackson, C. F. (Box 57)
  - Jackson, C. M. (Box 57)
  - Jackson, Holmes C. (Box 57)
  - Jackson, Homer W. (Box 57)
  - Jackson, R. Clay (Box 57)
  - Jackson, Sabra (Box 57)
  - Jacob, Arthur (Box 58)
  - Jacobs, Joseph (Box 58)
  - Jacobsen, A. Wilmot (Box 58)
  - Jacobsen, Hans R. (Box 58)
  - James, D. (Box 58)
  - James, Henry, Jr. (Box 58)
  - James, James M. (Box 58)
  - James, Mrs. Henry (Box 58)
  - James, Mrs. Walter B. (Box 58)
  - James, Oliver B. (Box 58)
  - James, Walter B. (Box 58)
  - Jameson, J. Franklin (Box 58)
  - Jameson, S. B. (Box 58)
  - Janet, Charles (Box 58)
  - Jansen, Mark (Box 58)
  - Jarvis, Philo (Box 58)
  - Jastro, Joseph (Box 58)
  - Jay, Delancey K (Box 58)
  - Jayne, Horace (Box 58)
  - Jayne, Mrs. Henry LeB. (Box 58)
  - Jeffray, Julia K. (Box 58)
  - Jelliffe, Smith Ely, 1893-1936; 3 folders (136 items) (Box 58)
    Biographical and personal data; Botany and plant genetics; Ecology; Editorial matters; Eugenics; Human genetics; Publication; World War I -- Impact on science
  - Jenkins, Elizabeth (Box 58)
  - Jenkins, George B., 1912-1929; 85 items (Box 58)
    Biographical and personal data; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Embryology, developmental genetics; Mouse genetics; Poultry genetics; World War I -- Impact on science
  - Jenkins, Mrs. S. (Box 58)
  - Jenks, A. E. (Box 58)
  - Jennings, Arthur L. (Box 58)
  - Jennings, Herbert S., 1897-1931; 4 folders (124 items) (Box 58)
    Biographical and personal data; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Evolution; Genetics; Human genetics; International Congress of Eugenics -- Second Congress; International Congress of Genetics -- Sixth Congress; International Congress of Zoology; Laboratory techniques, equipment; National Research Council -- Committee activities; Recommendations -- Morgan, Thomas Hunt; Recommendations -- Nobel Prize; Requests for aid in finding positions; Reviews; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Teaching; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Jennings, Mrs. Walter (Box 58)
  - Jennings, Walter (Box 58)
  - Jewett, Frances Gulick (Box 58)
  - Jewett, Frank Baldwin (Box 58)
  - Jobling, James W. (Box 58)
  - Johannsen, W. (Box 58)
  - Johns Hopkins University Press (Box 58)
  - Johnson, A. A. (Box 58)
  - Johnson, Albert (Box 58)
  - Johnson, Alexander (Box 58)
  - Johnson, Allen (Box 58)
  - Johnson, Alva (Box 58)
  - Johnson, Alvin (Box 58)
  - Johnson, Charles W. (Box 58)
  - Johnson, Duncan S., 1898-1932; 2 folders (77 items) (Box 58)
    Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Conferences and symposia; Ecology; Teaching; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements